Finding Aid for the John Jennings Papers, ca. 1940-1954
John Jennings Papers,
ca. 1940-1954
Jennings, John, 1906-
7 boxes (3.5 linear ft.)
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Dept. of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
John Edward Jennings, Jr. (1906-1973) was a author, writing under his own name and the pseudonyms Bates Baldwin and Joel Williams. His publications include Our American tropics (1938), Next to valour (1939), Boston, cradle of liberty, 1630-1776 (1945), The Salem frigate (1946), The sea eagles: a story of the American Navy during the Revolution (1950), The pepper tree: a story of New England and the Spice Islands (1950) and Banners against the wind (1954). Boxes 1-7 include galleys and typescript drafts.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
PARTIALLY PROCESSED COLLECTION UNAVAILABLE FOR USE: except for boxes 1-7. Inquiries regarding these materials should be directed, in writing, to the Manuscripts Librarian, UCLA Department of Special Collections.
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Biography
John Edward Jennings, Jr. was born on December 30, 1906 in Brooklyn, New York; attended Colorado School of Mines (1924-25), New York University (1925-26), and Columbia University (1927-28); graduated from Washington Diplomatic and Consular Institute, 1935; became author, writing under his own name and the pseudonyms Bates Baldwin and Joel Williams; publications include Our American tropics (1938), Next to valour (1939), Boston, cradle of liberty, 1630-1776 (1945), The Salem frigate (1946), The sea eagles: a story of the American Navy during the Revolution (1950), The pepper tree: a story of New England and the Spice Islands (1950), and Banners against the wind (1954); he died on December 4, 1973.
Scope and Content
Boxes 1-7 include galleys and typescript drafts.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Jennings, John, 1906- --Archives.; Authors, American--20th century--Archival resources.; Manuscripts for publication.
Container List
- The Sea Eagles, 1949., Corrected typescript. (Box 1)
- Gentleman Ranker, n.d., Galley proof. (Box 1)
- Boston Cradle of Liberty, n.d., Corrected typescript. (Box 2)
- Boston Cradle of Liberty, n.d., Galley proof. (Box 2)
- The Salem Frigate, n.d., Corrected original typescript. (Box 3)
- Boston Cradle of Liberty and The Salem Frigate, n.d., Scattered page proofs. (Box 3)
- The Salem Frigate, n.d., Carbon typescript, leaves 367-741). In green covers (uncut version). with Harold Matson printed on cover. (Box 3)
- The Salem Frigate, n.d., Carbon typescript, leaves 1-366. In green covers (uncut version). (Box 4)
- The Pepper Tree, n.d., Corrected typescript, 707 leaves. In brown covers. (Box 4)
- Banners Against The Wind, n.d., Corrected carbon typescript, 929 leaves. (Box 5)
- Banners Against The Wind, n.d., [Copy no.2 of original manuscript with first corrections]. In brown covers. (Box 5)
- The Pepper Tree (B Proof), 1950., Uncorrected galley proof. (Box 6)
- Call the New World, 1941., Uncorrected galley proof. (Box 6)
- Next to Valour, 1939., Uncorrected galley proof. (Box 6)
- Boston Cradle of Liberty, 1949., Corrected galley proof. (Box 7)
- The Salem Frigate, 1946., Corrected galley proof. (Box 7)